Guide to the Story of Italy Lecture Series, Yale University, Transcripts and Videotapes
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Story of Italy lecture series, Yale University, transcripts and videotapes
1974-1974
RU 835
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
5.5
The records consist of transcripts and U-matic videotapes of the Yale Story of Italy lectures series.
Yale University. Office of Public Information
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 4-C (YRG 4-C), Records documenting public information functions of Yale University.
Conditions Governing Access
These records are available for research.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged in two series: Series I. Transcripts of Lectures. Series II. Videotapes.
Biographical / Historical
The Story of Italy series, Yale University's first venture into educational programming for television, was organized by Thomas G. Bergin, Sterling Professor Emeritus of Romance Languages and prepared for television by the Office of Public Information. The series consists of thirty-five half-programs by faculty members on the history and culture of Italy. It aired on WTNH-TV in 1974 and 1975.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of transcripts and U-matic videotapes of the Yale Story of Italy lectures series.
Italy -- Study and teaching; Videotapes; Yale University. Office of Public Information
- Transcripts of Lectures, circa 1975; Series I
  - Series premiere. Thomas G. Bergin (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Italy: An Introduction. Ralph Marcarelli
  - The Legacy of Rome, Parts I and II. C.J. Herington (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Impact of the Barbarians, Parts I and II. Jeremy Adams (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Italian language. Howard Garey (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - A Survey of Italian painting 1300-1800, Part I. Charles Seymour, Jr. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Dante, Parts I and II. John Freccero (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Italy between Popes and emperors. Robert Lopez (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Petrarch. John Freccero (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Age of the city-state. Robert Lopez (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - A Survey of Italian painting 1300-1800, Part II. Charles Seymour, Jr. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bocaccio. Lowry Nelson, Jr. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Machiavelli. A. Bartlett Giamatti (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - A Survey of Italian painting 1300-1800, Part III. Charles Seymour, Jr. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Leonardo. David Cast (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - A Survey of Italian painting 1300-1800, Part IV. Charles Seymour, Jr. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Galileo. Derek DeSolla Price (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - The Beginning of opera in Florence. Claude Palisca (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Claudio Moteverdi. Claude Palisca (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - The Commedia dell'Arte. Jonathan Marks (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - The Italian opera in the nineteenth century. Robert Bailey (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Leopardi. Odile Veto (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Nineteenth and twentieth-century Italian sculpture. Timothy Verdon (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - The Italian tradition in experimental science. Derek DeSolla Price (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Croce: the story of a philosopher. John Smith (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Alberto Moravia. R.W.B. Lewis (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Modern Italian poetry. Thomas G. Bergin (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - The Modern Italian legal system. Guido Calabresi (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - The Continuity of the Italian cinema. M. Brandon French (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Italy on the edge of chaos. Joseph LaPalombara (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Governing with the Communists. Joseph LaPalombara (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Modern Rome. David Cast (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Videotapes, 1975; Series II
  - Premiere Program, videotape (U-matic) (Box 2)
  - Italy: An introduction. Ralph Marcarelli, videotape (U-matic) (Box 3)
  - The Legacy of Rome, Part I. C.J. Herington, videotape (U-matic) (Box 4)
  - The Legacy of Rome, Part II. C.J. Herington, videotape (U-matic) (Box 5)
  - The Impact of the barbarians, Part I. Jeremy Adams, videotape (U-matic) (Box 6)
  - The Impact of the barbarians, Part II. Jeremy Adams, videotape (U-matic) (Box 7)
  - The Italian language. Howard Garey, videotape (U-matic) (Box 8)
  - A Survey of Italian painting, 1300-1800, Part I. Charles Seymour, videotape (U-matic) (Box 9)
  - Dante, Part I, John Freccero, videotape (U-matic) (Box 10)
  - Dante, Part I, John Freccero [copy], 1 (Box 37)
  - Dante, Part II, John Freccero, videotape (U-matic) (Box 11)
  - Dante, Part II, John Freccero[copy], 1 (Box 38)
  - Italy between popes and emperors. Robert Lopez >, 1 (Box 12)
  - Petrarch. John Freccero, videotape (U-matic) (Box 13)
  - The Age of the City-State. Robert Lopez, videotape (U-matic) (Box 14)
  - A Survey of Italian painting, 1300-1800, Part II. Charles Seymour, videotape (U-matic) (Box 15)
  - Boccaccio. Lowry Nelson, Jr., videotape (U-matic) (Box 16)
  - Machiavelli. A. Bartlett Giamatti, videotape (U-matic) (Box 17)
  - Machiavelli. A. Bartlett Giamatti [copy], 1 (Box 39)
  - A Survey of Italian painting, 1300-1800, Part III. Charles Seymour, videotape (U-matic) (Box 18)
  - Leonardo. David Cast, videotape (U-matic) (Box 19)
  - Leonardo. David Cast [copy], 1 (Box 40)
  - A Survey of Italian painting, 1300-1800, Part IV. Charles Seymour, videotape (U-matic) (Box 20)
  - Galileo \( Italian contributions to science and technology, Part I?). Derek DeSolla Price, videotape (U-matic) (Box 21)
  - The Beginning of opera in Florence. Claude Palisca, videotape (U-matic) (Box 22)
  - Claudio Monteverdi. Claude Palisca, videotape (U-matic) (Box 23)
  - Commedia dell'Arte. Jonathan Marks, videotape (U-matic) (Box 24)
  - Italian opera in the Nineteenth Century. Robert Bailey, videotape (U-matic) (Box 25)
  - Leopardi. Odile Veto, videotape (U-matic) (Box 26)
  - Nineteenth and Twentieth-Century Italian sculpture. Timothy Verdon, videotape (U-matic) (Box 27)
  - The Italian tradition in experimental science \( Italian contributions to science and technology, Part II?), videotape (U-matic) (Box 28)
  - Croce: The Story of a Philosopher. John Smith, videotape (U-matic) (Box 29)
  - Alberto Moravia. R. W. B. Lewis, videotape (U-matic) (Box 30)
  - Modern Italian poetry. Thomas G. Bergin, videotape (U-matic) (Box 31)
  - The Modern Italian legal system: Some reflections. Guido Calabresi, videotape (U-matic) (Box 32)
  - The Italian cinema: 1910-1974. Brandon French, videotape (U-matic) (Box 33)
  - Italy on the edge of chaos. Joseph LaPalombara, videotape (U-matic) (Box 34)
  - Governing with the communists. Joseph LaPalombara, videotape (U-matic) (Box 35)
  - Modern Rome. David Cast, videotape (U-matic) (Box 36)